A Guide to the Hillenberg Store Records, 1896-1909
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Hillenberg Store Records 1896-1909
Special Collections, Kegley Library
2002.1
8 ledgers, 6 daybooks.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Gary and Ann Laing in 2002.
Historical Information
W. E. Hillenberg and Dr. Kincer operated a general merchandise store in Crockett, Virginia from 1896 to 1909. The store changed names over the years from Hillenberg and Kincer, Hillenberg and Dix, and W. E. Hillenberg and Sons.
Scope and Content
The eight ledgers in this collection (items 1-7, 10) have name indices at the beginning of each ledger that list customer names alphabetically and page references to transactions. Each transaction page generally gives customer name, description and cost of items purchased, date purchased, and debit and credit status of customer.
The six daybooks (items 8-9, 11-14) provide a daily transaction record, generally giving customer name, description, and cost of item purchased, and debit and credit status.
Contents List
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Kincer. 20 March 1896-1 July 1897., 372 p. with name index.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Kincer. 6 January 1898-1 January 1900., 470 p. with name index. Spine of ledger is loose.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Kincer. 1 January 1900-March 1901., 586 p. [p. 353-520 missing] with name index.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Kincer. March 1901-October 1903., 290 p. [p. 223-288 missing] with name index.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Dix. 1 January 1904-December 1904., 474 p. [p. 47-48; 387-458 missing] with name index.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Dix. 1 January 1905-December 1905., 510 p. [p. 1-2 missing] with name index.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Dix. 1904-1905., Produce book; 184 p. [p. 77-162 missing] with name index.
- Daybook. Hillenberg and Dix. 17 April 1905-20 October 1905., 494 p.
- Daybook. Hillenberg and Dix. 21 October 1905-24 July 1906., 497 p.
- Ledger. Hillenberg and Dix. April 1906-March 1908., 118 p. [p. 1-26 missing; p. 117-118 torn] without name index; no binding. Goods purchased from other vendors.
- Daybook. Hillenberg and Dix. 1 June 1907-29 January 1908., 600 p. [p. 597-600 loose].
- Daybook. W. E. Hillenberg and Sons. 1 February 1908-30 June 1908., 300 p.
- Daybook. W. E. Hillenberg and Sons. 1 July 1908-10 September 1908., 300 p.
- Daybook. W. E. Hillenberg and Sons. 10 December 1908-27 March 1909., 272 p.